PRATIK KUMAR

(+91) 9304642794 · pratikraj876@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/pratik1kumar

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

I have around **3+** years of experience as Oracle and SQL Server Production DBA handling databases for client-IAG. **Python developer** with 2 years' experience and commendable project performance. Proven skills in Django, Flask, and data analysis. Contributed to a significant efficiency increase in automation tasks. Have experience in handling Mission Critical Production Environment as well as in performing tasks as an Application DBA. Working as a Senior Database Administrator for DBA team. Providing support to different applications of IAG by guiding the application as well as production DBAs for better performance, supporting the application people directly and working for monitoring, maintenance and proper configurations of server, database and object settings.

SKILLS

- Language & Scripts: Python, SQL Server, Oracle DB, Pandas, NumPy, OpenCV
- Technologies & Tools: WinSCP, Putty, Mobaxterm, SSMS, SQL Developer, AWS, EC2, S3, PyCharm

EXPERIENCE

2021-Present COFORGE LTD.

Greater Noida, UP

IAG (Iberia) May2024 - Present

- Involved in Database creation and decommission as per requirement.
- Experience in Database user management and experience in managing the tablespace
- Managing control files, online redo logs, Archive logs.
- Experience in configuring and maintenance of Network Services (Listener and TNs Configuration).
- Experience in implementing complete Backup and recovery strategies using RMAN, Hot/Cold Backup, Logical (Import/Export, Data pump utilities).
- Creating and managing schemas, Roles, Privileges.
- Monitoring the ASM disk group and adding the disk to disk group when required.
- Experienced in Database patching.
- Regular monitoring of Alert log file on day-to-day basis.
- Worked extensively in migrating on-prem oracle dbs to AWS.
- Experience with AWS databases (RDS, Aurora and PostgreSQL)
- Configured an AWS Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) and Database Subnet Group for isolation of resources within the Confidential RDS Aurora DB cluster.

IAG (British Airways) Oct 2021 - May 2024

- Rewrite existing Python/Django modules to deliver certain format of data.
- Used Python IDE PyCharm for developing the code and performing the unit test.
- Designed and implemented server build automation & server decommissioning automation.
- Worked on ETL tasks like pulling, pushing data from and too various servers.
- \bullet Wrote Python and batch scripts to automate the ETL scripts runs every hour.
- Developed ETL scripts in Python to get data from one database table and insert, update the resultant data to another database table.
- Rewrote and optimized existing code, improving execution speed by 30%

EDUCATION

2017-2021 GALGOTIAS UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Technology Computer Science & Engineering

2016-2017 RAJDHANI PUBLIC SCHOOL

12th

2014-2015 S.R.T SCHOOL

10th

CERTIFICATE

- Microsoft certified azure fundamental
- Microsoft certified azure database administrator associate

LANGUAGE

- Hindi (native)
- English

STRENGTH

- Positive thinker
- Good listener
- Self-motivated
- Good problem-solving skills